Guide to the Research Libraries Group Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Research Libraries Group, records
1972-1987
SC0270
Research Libraries Group.
Research Libraries Group
19.5 Linear feet
Reports, manuals, proposals, surveys, statistics; BALLOTS System books and reference manuals; PLAN Systems books.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, Research Libraries Group, 1981 and 2000.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Reports, manuals, proposals, surveys, statistics; BALLOTS System books and reference manuals; PLAN Systems books.
Access Terms
Kass, Tina; Research Libraries Group.; Stanford University. Ballots Center.; Ballots Project.; Machine-readable bibliographic data.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Reports and Publications
    - Rosenthal, Joseph A. The Research Libraries Group; Proposals for Cooperation among the Libraries of Columbia, Harvard, and Yale Universities and the New York Public Library. December 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Stanford University Response to Research Libraries Groups, Inc. Request for Proposals for an Automated Bibliographic Control System. October 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Stanford University's Response to the University of California Request for Quotation and Proposal. Universitywide Library Technical Processing System. BALLOTS Center Stanford University April 21, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A Plan for Development of a Research Libraries Network Based upon the BALLOTS System. Research Libraries Group, Inc., and Stanford University July 1978. Draft. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Final Report of the BALLOTS Center to the National Endowment for the Humanities on Grant Activities from January 1, 1975 to May 31, 1978. Stanford University, February 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A Plan for the Development of a Research Libraries Information Network. The Research Libraries Group, Inc. October 20, 1978. Revised and Abridged January 4, 1979. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Research Libraries Group, Inc. Progress Report. June 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - RLG Terminal Manual Zentec 9003 and Zentec ZMS-90 Video Terminals. August 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Technical Report on Linking the Bibliographic Utilities: Benefits and Costs. Submitted to the Council on Library Resources September 15, 1980 by Donald A. Smalley, William G. Griffith, Ann M. Walker, Michael B. Wessells (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - On-Line Public Access to Library Bibliographic Data Bases: Developments, Issues and Priorities. Final Report to the Council on Library Resources. September 1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Shurkin, Joel. " The Rise and Fall and Rise of RLG." American Libraries July/August 1982. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Proposal for the Development of an Integrated Local Library System Based on RLIN/ASPEN. Research Libraries Group, Inc. 30 November 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Processing and Data Distribution within the Research Libraries Information Network. Final Report to the Carnegie Corporation of New York on a Study of Distributed Processing. November 1983. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - RLIN System Reference Manual. First edition March 1984. The Research Libraries Group, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - A Technical Overview of RLIN. 29 May 1984 Research Libraries Group, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - The Name Authority Cooperative/Name Authority File Service. Task Force on a Name Authority File Service. Bibliographic Service Development Program. Council on Library Resources, Inc. May 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Issues in Retrospective Conversion. Report of a study conducted for the Council on Library Resources by Jutta Reed-Scott. May 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Retrospective Conversion. Report of a meeting sponsored by the Council on Library Resources July 16-18, 1984. Compiled and edited by Dorothy Gregor, September 1984. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Command Language and Screen Displays for Public Online Systems. Report of a meeting sponsored by the Council on Library Resources March 29-30 1984. Compiled and Edited by Paul Evan Peters. March 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Stanford University Libraries. Library Automation Proposal. December 29, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Loose materials from binder containing Stanford University Libraries Library Automation Proposal. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - BALLOT materials to be part of SC 270 (some materials are marked 6351)
    - Stanford University Response to RLIN Request for Proposals for an Automated Bibiolgraphic Control System: BALLOTS, October 1977 - 2 binders
    - Stanford University's Response to the University of California Request for Quotation and Proposal: Universitywide Library Technical Processing System, April 21, 1978 - 1 binder
    - A Plan for the Development of a Research Libraries Information Network, October 1978 - 1 binder
    - Bibliographic Automation of Large Library Operations Using a Time-Sharing System: Phase II, Part I (July 1970-June 1971) - final report, Februry 1972
    - System Scope for Library Automation and Generalized Information Storage and Retrieval at Stanford U niversity ¬ - report 1970 (printed 1972)
    - Project BALLOTS; Bibliographic Automation of Large Library Operations Using a Time-Sharing System - progress reports July 29, 1969; November 21, 1969; and December 26, 1969
    - Stanford University Data File Directory, July 1973
    - Information Retrieval (SPIRES) and Library Automation (BALLOTS) at Stanford University, November 1970
    - Working Paper on the Future of Library Automation at Stanford, David C. Weber, September 1971
    - A Feasibility Study on the Participation of Four Colleges and Universities in a Stanford Library Automation Network, Volume 1, July 1971
    - Draft Proposal for the Bibiolographical Automation of Large Library Operations Using a Time-Sharing System (Project BALLOTS), February 1967
    - Bibiolographical Automation of Large Library Operations Using a Time-Sharing System (Project BALLOTS), proposal, May 1967
  - Folders:
    - Memos to library staff re BALLOTS, 1974-78
    - Misc. Information (brochures, guides, etc), 1968-75
    - Bibiolographical Automation of Large Library Operations Using a Time-Sharing System, Final Report, September 1970 - xerox of computer printout
    - Misc. reports and memos